Guide to the Dorothy Allison Papers, 1965-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Dorothy Allison papers 1965-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Allison, Dorothy.
92.5 Linear Feet 69,375 Items
Dorothy Allison is an author and feminist who has written numerous books and short stories, including Trash (1988), Bastard Out of Carolina (1992), and Cavedweller (1998).
The Dorothy Allison Papers include drafts and manuscripts of her writings (including Bastard Out of Carolina, Trash, Cavedweller, and other works), personal and professional correspondence, research materials and subject files, her personal journals, and other materials. Includes some photographs, electronic files, and oversize materials. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
All of Allison's journals are restricted and require permission from their creator prior to use.
All of Allison's unpublished works are restricted and require written permission from their creator for access and copying.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Dorothy Allison Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2010.
Biographical Note
Dorothy Allison was born on April 11, 1949 in Greenville, South Carolina, and grew up as the oldest child of an unwed, teenage mother. She was the first member of her family to graduate from high school. She earned her B.A. in 1971 from Florida Presbyterian (now Eckerd) College, which she attended on a National Merit Scholarship. Allison subsequently did graduate work in anthropology at Florida State University, The Sagaris Institute, and the New School for Social Research, where she earned a M.A. in urban anthropology in 1981.
From 1973-1974, she was the editor of the feminist magazine Amazing Grace, in Tallahassee Florida. From 1973-1974, she was a founding manager of Herstore Feminist Bookstore in Tallahassee. She was also an editor at Quest from 1976-1979
Allison's writings were originally published in Quest, Conditions, and Outlook, early lesbian and gay journals. Her chapbook of poetry, The Women Who Hate Me, was first published by Long Haul Press in 1983. Her short story collection, Trash, was first published by Firebrand Books in 1988, winning two Lambda Literary Awards and the American Library Association Prize for Lesbian and Gay Writing.
She received mainstream recognition with her first novel, Bastard Out of Carolina, published by Dutton and a finalist for the 1992 National Book Prize. The book was a best seller and was made into an award-winning movie. Subsequent books included Skin: Talking about Sex, Class, and Literature, a group of narrative essays published by Firebrand Books in 1994, and Two or Three Things I Know for Sure, published by Dutton in 1995. Cavedweller, published in 1998, was lauded as a New York Times notable book, and also became a best seller. Allison continues to write, speak, lecture, and teach in writing workshops, colleges, women's studies departments and organizations, and feminist and activist groups.
This biographical note was created in part from information provided on Allison's website, dorothyallison.net.
Collection Overview
The Dorothy Allison Papers include drafts and manuscripts of her writings (including Bastard Out of Carolina, Trash, Cavedweller, and other works). All of Allison's unpublished works are RESTRICTED and require permission from the creator prior to use. Personal and professional correspondence, including exchanges with her publishers and other authors, are held in the chronological and work files. The collection also contains Allison's research materials and subject files, covering topics on feminism, lesbianism, sexuality, pornography, writing, and other related files. Allison's journals, dating from 1985 through the 2000s, consist of both handwritten and electronic formats, with all of the electronic journals printed for the archive. All of Allison's journals are RESTRICTED and require permission from the creator prior to use. Also included are materials from her speaking engagements, workshops, and other professional activities. There are a variety of special formats within the collection, including some photographs, electronic files, audio tapes, video cassettes, DVDs, and oversize posters.
Collection was acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Allison, Dorothy
Allison, Dorothy -- Bastard Out of Carolina
Allison, Dorothy -- Trash
Allison, Dorothy -- Cavedweller
American literature -- History and criticism
American literature -- Southern States
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence
Authors and publishers
Feminism and literature -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Lesbianism in literature
Literature -- Study and teaching
Pornography -- Censorship
Pornography -- Political aspects -- United States
Sadomasochism
Women and literature -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Women authors, American
Diaries
Contents of Collection
- Subject Files Series, 1974-1998 and undated, (31 boxes)
  These materials consist of Allison's research files.
  Allison's original order has been retained. Boxes 1-26 are in alphabetical order, with separate subseries for extensive sections on pornography and sadomasochism (S/M). Boxes 27-31 contain a separate subseries of non-alphabetical subject files.
  - Aarens, Blake (Box 1)
  - Deborah Abbot
  - Abbot, Shirley. Why Southern Women Leave Home. (Box 1)
  - Woodruff, Judy, Ellen Willis, Linda Gordon, Sidney Callahan, Ellen Fielding. Is Abortion the Issue. Harpers. (Box 1)
  - Kathy Acker. Empire of the Senseless. (Box 1)
  - Act-Up (Box 1)
  - Against Sadomasochism (Book from Frog in the Well Press) (Box 1)
  - AI: Flamm, M. Review of SIN Voice, July, 1986. (Box 1)
  - AIDS: Hardy, Robin. Safe Sex. Voice 20 June, 1990. (Box 1)
  - AIDS: Is the Rectum a Grave? (Box 1)
  - AIDS: Lesbians and Aids (Box 1)
  - Alarcón, Francisco X. (Box 1)
  - Albrecht, Lisa. The Woman Writer Empowered. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Paula Gunn (Box 1)
  - Almáquer, Tomás. Remembering Ms. Lee, by Alberto Acuña (Box 1)
  - Alyson Publications, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Ameen, Mark (Box 1)
  - American Writers Conference 1981 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood. Hands. (Box 1)
  - Anthropologist as Writer: Geertz, Clifford (Box 1)
  - Anzaldúa, Gloria (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Madelyn. Daddy's Girl (On Ships at Sea) (Box 1)
  - Arnone, Joann (Box 1)
  - Astraea Fund (Box 1)
  - Astuto, Cynthia S. (Box 1)
  - Astrological charts (Box 1)
  - Margaret Atwood interview (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical first novels (Box 1)
  - Going to Have a Baby? flier, Berkeley, CA, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Balaban, John. Words for my Daughter (poem) (Box 1)
  - Baldi, Malaga (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Guy. Drummer columns (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, James (Box 1)
  - Barrington, Judith. The Flight of the Mind. (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Allen. The Body and its Dangers. (Box 1)
  - Barrus, Tim. Knights Press (Box 1)
  - Barry, Lynda (Box 1)
  - Battered Women (Box 1)
  - The Will to Beauty. Vanity Fair, Dec. 1983 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Madison. Less is Less (On Anorexic fiction) (Box 1)
  - Bellamy, Dodie (Box 1)
  - Belle Lettres (Box 1)
  - Bellum, Dan (Box 1)
  - Benderson, Bruce (Box 1)
  - Bernhard, Sandra (Box 1)
  - Bigelow, Kathryn (Box 2)
  - Biggs, Mary. Women's Literary Journals (Box 2)
  - Biggs, Mary. Conditions review (Box 2)
  - Birdfeather, Robin (Box 2)
  - Sally R. Binford articles (Box 2)
  - Binford, Sally R. articles (Box 2)
  - Becky Birtha (Box 2)
  - Bisexuals (Box 2)
  - The Bishop.Fanni Hill. (Box 2)
  - Joreen. The Bitch Manifesto. (Box 2)
  - Black Queers (Box 2)
  - Bloom, Amy (Box 2)
  - Bloom, Harold (Box 2)
  - Bono, Chastity (Box 2)
  - Booklist (Box 2)
  - Borges, Jorge Luis The Secret Miracle from Labyrinths (Box 2)
  - Boston, MA (Box 2)
  - Bound & Gagged (Male bondage magazine) (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Bill (Box 2)
  - Paul Bowles. by Geoffrey O'Brien (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Blanche. Black Hand Girl. (Box 2)
  - Boyle, T. Coraghessan. Peace of Mind. (Box 2)
  - Boys With Arms Akimbo (Box 2)
  - Bradley, Marion Zimmer (Box 2)
  - Braindrop, Lilly. Taste of Latex. (Box 2)
  - Brant, Beth E.: Turtle Gal (Box 2)
  - Brava (Box 2)
  - Bright, Suzie (Box 2)
  - A Vegetarian Briss (Box 2)
  - Brossard, Nichole (Box 2)
  - Brownstein, Michael. Music from the Evening of the World (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Louise - Lulu (Box 2)
  - Brown, Dr. Deborah (Beth) (Box 2)
  - Brown, Jan (Vancouver, BC) (Box 2)
  - Brown, Rebecca (Box 2)
  - Brown, Rita Mae (Box 2)
  - Brownmiller, Susan. Waverly Place. (Box 2)
  - Buffalo Lesbian Community Madeline Davis and Elizabeth Kennedy (Box 2)
  - Bulkin, Elly and Rena Grasso Patterson, Annette Koldony and Judith Gardiner. Feminist Criticism (Box 2)
  - Bunch, Charlotte - lectures (Box 2)
  - Burroughs, William S. (Box 2)
  - Bursk, Christopher. Tying My Wrists (Box 2)
  - Butch/Femme discussion (Box 2)
  - Butler, Judy (feminist, lesbian philosopher) (Box 2)
  - Butler, Octavia (Box 2)
  - Cadigan, Pat. Patterns. 1987. (Box 3)
  - Caesar Salad (Box 3)
  - Califia, Pat. Macho Sluts critique (Box 3)
  - Women's Cancer Resource Center (Box 3)
  - Capote, Truman (Box 3)
  - Carnality and Conservatism. 1986 (Box 3)
  - Carr, Cindy (Box 3)
  - Carter, Angela. Nothing Sacred review (Box 3)
  - Carver, Raymond (Box 3)
  - Cathexis: Robin Birdfeather (Box 3)
  - Caught Looking (Judith Levine review, 1987) (Box 3)
  - Censorship (Box 3)
  - Centrum Fort Worden State Park Writing Retreat (Box 3)
  - Chapkis, Wendy (Box 3)
  - Chase, Joan (Box 3)
  - Cheever, John (Box 3)
  - Chester, Mark (Box 3)
  - Chicago (Box 3)
  - Chrystos (Box 3)
  - Cirby (leather artist) (Box 3)
  - CLAGS - 1988-1994 (Committee on Lesbian and Gay Studies) (Box 3)
  - Chevigny, Belle Gale. Chloe and Olivia. (Box 3)
  - Birtha, Becky on Cheryl Clarke (Box 3)
  - Cisneros, Sandra (Box 3)
  - Clarke, Cheryl on Audre Lorde (Box 3)
  - Class and feminism (Box 3)
  - Clausen, Jan. The Political Morality of Fiction,Interesting Condition (Box 3)
  - Cliff, Michelle (Box 3)
  - Cohen, Belissa (Box 3)
  - C.O.L.D. (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Wanda. Deja Veca. (Box 3)
  - Collectives, Dorothy Allison (Box 3)
  - Constance Enterprises (Box 3)
  - Cooper, Dennis (Box 3)
  - Cordova, Jeanne. Androgyny of Spirit, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Cottingham, Laura. Pornography, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Crews, Harry (Box 3)
  - Crimp, Douglas (Act Up) (Box 3)
  - Cruickshank, Peg. Lesbian Literature: Some random thoughts, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Cultural feminism (Box 3)
  - Cunningham, Michael (Box 3)
  - Curzon, Daniel (Box 3)
  - Pat Califia writings (Box 4-5)
  - Corset patterns (Box 6)
  - Dallas leather and S/M conference, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Dattile, Rickey (Box 7)
  - Daughters, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Davis, Thulani on Black women writers, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Dear World ... (Box 7)
  - Decision Hafiza Hafill (Kennebec: A Portfolio of Maine Writing) (Box 7)
  - Delaney, Samuel; gay fiction boycott (Box 7)
  - DeLynn, Jane, 1988 (Box 7)
  - de Man, Paul pro-Nazi writings (Box 7)
  - Denneny, Michael. The Universal Voice of Gay Writers, 1987 (Box 7)
  - D'Erasmo, Stacey. Isabel's Sister is Grinding Her Teeth, O, Angel Boy. (Box 7)
  - Derricotte, Toi (Box 7)
  - Dexter, Pete (Box 7)
  - Diets (Box 7)
  - Dimen, Muriel. Seven Notes for the Reconstruction of Sexuality. (Box 7)
  - Dixon, Melvin (Box 7)
  - Dlugos, Tim, 1950-1995 (Box 7)
  - Dougherty, Cecillia (Box 7)
  - Drawing the Line: Lesbian Sex and Art (Box 7)
  - Doctorow, E.L. The Passion of our calling. (Box 7)
  - Dodson, Betty. Confessions of a female pornographer (Box 7)
  - Doughty, Frances (Box 7)
  - Drabble, Margaret (Box 7)
  - Drummond, Jeff. Of InHuman Bondage, 1989. (Box 7)
  - Duberman, Martin (Box 7)
  - Dubois, Ellen, and Linda Gordon. Ecstasy on the Battlefield: Danger and Pleasure in Nineteenth Century Feminist Sexual Thought (Box 7)
  - Duggin, Lisa - Eleanor Roosevelt (Box 7)
  - Dunn, Katherine (Box 7)
  - Dunne, John Gregory. Harp, 1989. (Box 7)
  - Dworkin, Andrea: Lesbian Pride, Why Right Wing Women Hate Gays, First Love (Box 7)
  - Andrea Dworkin by Erica Jong (Box 7)
  - Duras, Marguerite (Box 7)
  - Dyketactics: Philadelphia (Box 7)
  - DYKE (Box 7)
  - Eaton, Dossie (Box 7)
  - Echols, Alice. Cultural Feminism: F. Capitalism and Anti Porn movement, 1983. (Box 7)
  - Effinger, George. Slow, Slow Burn. (Box 7)
  - Ehrenreich, Hess, Jacobs. Re-Making Love: The Feminization of Sex, 1986. (Box 7)
  - Elgin, Suzette Haden. The Lonesome Node. (Box 7)
  - Ellis, Bret Easton (Box 7)
  - Ellison, Harlan. Hard Truths and Sage Advice. (Box 7)
  - Emecheta, Buchi (Box 7)
  - Erdrich, Louise. Matchimanotir, Beet Queen Love Medicine. (Box 7)
  - Escoffier, Jeff (Box 7)
  - Ewert, Mark (Box 7)
  - Exile (Harpers) (Box 7)
  - FACT (Feminist Anti-Censorship Task force) (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, Barbara (Lehman College intern) (Box 8)
  - Fat liberation (Box 8)
  - Ferro-Grumley Foundation and Prize (Box 8)
  - Fein, Cheri, short story about Galen Williams (Box 8)
  - Feingold, Michael. AIDS, Mourning and Action, 1990. (Box 8)
  - Feist, Nikki (Box 8)
  - Valenti, Chi Chi. Two Women (Box 8)
  - Fierstein, Harvey (Box 8)
  - Finley, Karen (Box 8)
  - Flannagan, Bob (Box 8)
  - Rohem, Ned, on Janet Flanner. Remembering Janet. (Box 8)
  - Flegel, Laura (Box 8)
  - Folayan, Ayofemi (Box 8)
  - Ford, Richard. My Mother in Memory, 1987. (Box 8)
  - Fornes, Maria Irene - Cherrie Moraga (Box 8)
  - Forché, Carolyn. El Salvador: An Aide-Mémoire. (Box 8)
  - Foucault, Michel (Box 8)
  - Frankel, Martha (Box 8)
  - Fritz, Leah. Is there sex after sadomasochism? 1983. (Box 8)
  - Fund for Human Dignity (Box 8)
  - Furies (Box 8)
  - GCN (Box 8)
  - Gaitskill, Mary (Box 8)
  - Gordimer, Nadine (Box 8)
  - Gardinier, Suzanne, 1990 (Box 8)
  - William H. Gass, Art and Morality (Box 8)
  - G.A.U. (Box 8)
  - The Futures of Gay America (Box 8)
  - Gay businesses in San Francisco area (Box 8)
  - Rich, Frank. The Gay Decade, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Gay fiction by Daniel Harris (Box 8)
  - Gay and Lesbian publishing, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Gay male porn language and images (Box 8)
  - Gay writers (Box 8)
  - The Gay Sensibility, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Gay studies (Box 8)
  - Celebration '90 - Gay Games, Vancouver, BC, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Gaylactic Network (Box 8)
  - Gibson, William (Box 8)
  - Gilchrist, Ellen (Box 8)
  - Glaser, Nina (Box 8)
  - Gluck, Bob (Box 8)
  - Godwin, Marie. Touched by Stubbornness, 1983. (Box 8)
  - Goldin, Nan (Box 8)
  - Goldsby, Jackie (Box 9)
  - I want the Mike, Phil: On Racism and the Gay Community and Cannon Fodder: The Politics of (Re)Constructing Gay/Lesbian History (Box 9)
  - Golding, Susan. Lesbian Sex, Politics. (Box 9)
  - Goldstein: Notes on Camping and The Politics of Liberation (Box 9)
  - Gomez, Jewelle. Imagine a lesbian ... a black lesbian and poetry mss. (Box 9)
  - Good, Patricia - student (Box 9)
  - Gordon, Linda. Child Sex Abuse (Box 9)
  - Gornick, Vivian (Box 9)
  - Gossett, Hattie (Box 9)
  - Grae, Della. Love Bites (Box 9)
  - Grace, Camarin. Winged Dancer, Paz, and Soul Snatcher (Box 9)
  - Graff, E.J. (Box 9)
  - Graham, Nan. Women Editors. (Box 9)
  - Gray, Francine du Plessix. In Praise of Idleness. (Box 9)
  - Greer, Germaine.The Sisterhood: The True Story Behind the Women's Movement, 1998. (Box 9)
  - Grossberger, Louis. Mental Notes. (Box 9)
  - Grover, Jan Zita (Box 9)
  - Grumbach, Doris (Box 9)
  - Guerilla Girls (Box 9)
  - Guido, Beatriz. The Usurper. (Box 9)
  - Gurganis, Alan (Box 9)
  - Hacker, Marilyn/Cheryl Clarke (Box 9)
  - Haggard, Merle (Box 9)
  - Hall, Richard (Box 9)
  - Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center (Box 9)
  - Hambridge Center: Rabun Gap, GA (Box 9)
  - Hamilton, Jane. When I began to understand Quantum Mechanics, 1989. (Box 9)
  - Hampton, Mabel (Box 9)
  - Haring, Keith (Box 9)
  - Harjo, Joy (Box 9)
  - Harris, Bertha (Box 9)
  - Harryman, Carla (Box 10)
  - Halperin, Daniel. Homos and History. (Box 10)
  - Hay, Harry. Roots, 1988. (Box 10)
  - Headlands Center for the Arts (Box 10)
  - Hearne, Vicki (Box 10)
  - Heinemann, Larry (Box 10)
  - Helfand, Judy. Sexual Outlaw. (Box 10)
  - Hellfire (Box 10)
  - Helms, Jesse (Box 10)
  - Hemphill, Essex (Box 10)
  - Henley, Patricia. The Secret of Cartwheels. (Box 10)
  - Alice Henry Takes WAP Porn Tour, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Herstore, Tallahassee, Florida (Box 10)
  - High Risk reviews (Box 10)
  - Hill, Anita (Box 10)
  - San Francisco Bay Area Gay and Lesbian Historical Society (Box 10)
  - Hite, Shere. What Men Don't Know About Women, 1982. (Box 10)
  - Hoagland, Edward. Writers are sleeping, 1990. (Box 10)
  - Hoagland, Sarah (Box 10)
  - Hodges, Beth. Lesbian Feminist Writing and Publishing, 1975. (Box 10)
  - Kaminsky, Marc on Abbie Hoffman (Box 10)
  - Hollander, Anne. Tight Lacing, 1982. (Box 10)
  - Hollibaugh, Amber. Writers as activists, Feminist Anger, Sexual Despair, Erotophobia. (Box 10)
  - Homes, A.M. (Box 10)
  - Homophobia (Box 10)
  - Homosexualities, Amsterdam conference, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Hosukai. Tale of the Fishermans Wife. (Box 10)
  - Houston, Pam. Jackson is Only One of My Dogs. (Box 10)
  - Howard, Richard (Box 10)
  - Hughes, Holly (Box 10)
  - Hunger, Nan - Feminist Chronology (Box 10)
  - Hurston, Zora Neale (Box 10)
  - Huston, Bo. The Bath (Box 10)
  - Impact (Box 10)
  - Incest (Box 10)
  - Incest Survivors Anonymous (Box 10)
  - Gary, Indiana. Scenes from my book tour. (Box 10)
  - International Mr. Leather (Box 10)
  - IMsL (International Ms. Leather), 1988 (Box 10)
  - Ianieri, Christine (Box 10)
  - Isherwood, Christopher (Box 10)
  - Jackson, Earle (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Jackson, LaToya, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Jay, Karla, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Jenkins, Edith, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Deborah (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Fenton (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Jill (Box 11)
  - Jones, Judith (Box 11)
  - Jong, Erica. Autobiography as fiction/Fiction as autobiography. (Box 11)
  - Joplin, Janis (Box 11)
  - Jordan, June. For the Sake of a People's Poetry: Walt Whitman and the rest of us. (Box 11)
  - Kafka, Franz. The Hunger Artist. (Box 11)
  - Carter, Angela, on Frida Kahlo (Box 11)
  - Kaye, Melanie (Box 11)
  - Kendrick, Walter, book proposal and reviews (Box 11)
  - Kerr, Barbara (Box 11)
  - Killian, Kevin (Box 11)
  - Kincaid, Jamaica (Box 11)
  - Kingston, Maxine Hong, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Kingsolver, Barbara (Box 11)
  - Klein, Margeaux (Box 11)
  - Klepfisz, Irena (Box 11)
  - Koedt, Anne. The Myth of the Vaginal Orgasm. (Box 11)
  - Kranidas, Kathleen. Short Story Writing. (Box 11)
  - Kunzle, David. Special Historic and Psychological Role of Tight Lacing, 1982. (Box 11)
  - Kureishi, Hanif. Esther. (Box 11)
  - Laidlaw, Marc (Box 12)
  - Lambda Rising Book Report and Literary Awards, Washington, DC (Box 12)
  - Latzky, Eric (Box 12)
  - Leathersex (Box 12)
  - Leavitt, David (Box 12)
  - LeGuin, Ursula (Box 12)
  - Leibowitz, Fran. Impact of AIDS on the Artistic Community, 1987. (Box 12)
  - Leiter, Jonathan (Box 12)
  - Leidholdt, Dorchen. Lesbians S/M: Sexual Radicalism or Reaction. (Box 12)
  - Levenstein, Cathy (Box 12)
  - Lesbian Agenda for Action Conference, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Lesbians - modern types (Box 12)
  - Lessing, Doris (Box 12)
  - Levine, Judith (Box 12)
  - Lewin, Rebecca (Box 12)
  - Laura Gotswitz's film interviews: Dorchen, Urania, Bonnie Klein (Box 12)
  - Lesbianism packet (Box 12)
  - Wilson, Elizabeth. Forbidden Love. (Box 12)
  - Lesbian Herstory Archives Newsletter (Box 12)
  - Links Calendar (Box 12)
  - Lindenbaum, Shirley (Box 12)
  - LSM Speakout, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Lammas. Little Review. (Box 12)
  - Lookists, Fat oppression, p.c. (Box 12)
  - Lorde, Audre (Box 12)
  - Los Angeles (Box 12)
  - JoAnn Loulan lesbian sex (Box 12)
  - Love: Romantic Love, 1988. (Box 12)
  - Lyon, Lisa (Box 12)
  - McCullers, Carson (Box 13)
  - McCombs, Anne - letter to Ms. (Box 13)
  - McDaniel, Judith. Lesbians and Literature. (Box 13)
  - McDonald, Scott. Confessions of a Feminist Porn Watcher. (Box 13)
  - MacDowell Colony (Box 13)
  - McEnery, Jay on critics (Box 13)
  - McEwen, Christian (Box 13)
  - MacKinnon, Catharine (Box 13)
  - McGuire, Dawn (Box 13)
  - McMahan, Jeffrey N. (Box 13)
  - McNaron, Toni (Box 13)
  - McLaughlin, Laurie (Box 13)
  - Mach, Henry. My Life in Porn, 1986. (Box 13)
  - Madonna (Box 13)
  - Magister, Thom (Box 13)
  - Maggenti, Maria. The Politics of Ambition, Rich Dykes. (Box 13)
  - Malcomson, Scott, Ethnography, 1989 (Box 13)
  - Mansfield, Katherine (Box 13)
  - Mapplethorpe - Women (Box 13)
  - Margins (Box 13)
  - Mason, Bobbie Ann (Box 13)
  - Mayo, Anna. Feminisms in an Indigo Mood. (Box 13)
  - Meigs, Mary (Box 13)
  - Miller, Lee (Box 13)
  - Millet, Kate (Box 13)
  - Miner, Valerie (Box 13)
  - Minh-ha, Trinh T. Grandma's Story. (Box 13)
  - Mirosevich, Tori (Box 13)
  - Yourcenar. Mishima. (Box 13)
  - Mitchell, Pam (Box 13)
  - Monette, Paul (Box 13)
  - Monteflores, Carmen de (Box 14)
  - Moraga, Cherrie. Hungry Women; Giving Up the Ghost. (Box 14)
  - Moraga, Cherrie (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Morgan, Robin (Box 14)
  - Morrison, Toni (Box 14)
  - Morton, Shadow. Last Moon Rising. (Box 14)
  - Movement history (Box 14)
  - Motheroot Review (Box 14)
  - Women and motorcycles (Box 14)
  - Motorcycles - Edelweiss Bike Tours (Box 14)
  - Mukherjee, Bharati (Box 14)
  - Multiculturalism (Box 14)
  - Murphy, Pat (Box 14)
  - Munro, Alice (Box 14)
  - Murragy, Marea. Women See Women. (Box 14)
  - Leger, Mark. My Comrade. (Box 14)
  - Myles, Eileen (Box 14)
  - Naiad Press and Film Rights for Desert Hearts, 1986. (Box 15)
  - National Book Awards (Box 15)
  - Nava, Michael (Box 15)
  - Davis, L.J. Ballad of an American Terrorist: A Neo-Nazi's Dream Order. (Box 15)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 15)
  - Nelson, Linda (Box 15)
  - Nestor, Cathy (Box 15)
  - New Women's Review Index, 1983-1987 (Box 15)
  - New Words Bookstore, Boston, MA (Box 15)
  - Newton, Helmut (Playboy) (Box 15)
  - NY Human Rights Commission: AIDS Unit: The Epidemiology of Stigma. (Box 15)
  - New York (Box 15)
  - Newton, Esther. Alice-Hunting. (Box 15)
  - Notwithstanding, Nicolai. Initiation. (Box 15)
  - NOW Resolution on Lesbian and Gay Rights Protest (Box 15)
  - Not a Love Story (Box 15)
  - Nugent, Beth. City of Boys. (Box 15)
  - OakGrove, Artemis (Box 15)
  - O'Connor, Flannery (Box 15)
  - Off Our Backs, 1982 (Box 15)
  - O'Dair, Barbara. Sex, Love, Desire: Feminists Struggle over the Portrayal of Sex. (Box 15)
  - O'Keefe, Georgia (Box 15)
  - Olds, Sharon (Box 15)
  - Oliver, Sharma (Box 15)
  - Orlando, Lisa. Lust at Last, 1982. (Box 15)
  - Out Magazine (Box 15)
  - Outing (Box 15)
  - Outwrite, Boston, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Pornography Subseries
    This subseries contains Allison's research files on pornography.
    - People Magazine: Meese Commission (Box 16)
    - MacKinnon, Catharine sues Elsa Gidlow (Box 16)
    - Ehrenreich, Hess and Jacobs.Fundamentalist Sex. (Box 16)